[Music]
oh
cool
so i was watching um
shkreli's finance lectures
and he gave
lectures with a list of
it's it's kind of financial advice and
he starts out by saying
what is finance he breaks it down into
well okay if you want to get into it you
have a choice you can either invest your
own money or other people's money
um investing your own money probably
only makes sense if you have a lot of it
you need tools to uh
right like there's no reason you should
be investing your money if somebody else
can invest it better
basically good advice um so i thought
i'd do something similar for programming
i was watching i i googled
how to learn to program
uh let's let's let's do this how to
learn
to program
also again like you guys think i'm on
drugs constantly i'm really not
um i smoke weed occasionally
i drink occasionally i don't really do
harder drugs than that
uh i don't think i've taken adderall or
any other stimulants this year
i don't know why you guys all think that
maybe there's something defective about
my brain chemistry
so i'm not going to teach you vim
if you think you want to learn park type
thank you for subscribing and i'm hoping
to get a lot of subscribers for this
stream because
i'm going to try to educate instead of
just
a lot of times when i talk i'm not
trying to
be made sense of i'm not
i'm trying to i'm thinking out loud and
i'm not trying to
explain things such that an audience
will understand
so we could say yeah look i can tell you
here here's lifehacker.com the best ways
to teach yourself to code
and really it comes down to just doing
it
like almost everything but i think a
question a lot of people have is what
exactly do i do
so let's
let's bring them up here and let's talk
about what a program
is okay so you have a program what's the
definition of a program
well um
you can think about it like this a
program takes in some input
does some computation and produces some
output
so there's an argument to be made that
we should be teaching
kids how to program using functional
languages because functional languages
more closely match this paradigm
but computers don't operate
like functions computers operate a lot
more like turing machines which we can
get into too so maybe
on one side of an extreme uh we have
like a high-level functional programming
language like haskell
and then let's not really go lower than
c c and assembly r
c and assembly are the same structurally
so you can treat c and assembly like the
same thing see this kind of assembly
with a bit of syntactic sugar around it
there's nothing in c that doesn't very
clearly map
to something in assembly um
please subscribe i hope you guys like
this kind of content okay
so let's say like languages uh span the
gamut
from c uh over to haskell right
um then you can take languages and
languages go in a few directions
you can think of this as like the
functional spectrum
uh and then maybe there's c over to
python
and this is kind of the ease of use
spectrum
so in the 90s it was believed that
object oriented programming
was going to be this revolution in
programming that's c going to c
plus plus right um basically and
you can take it even further microsoft
created these things called
com objects and everything was going to
be an object
to pass around small talk has this kind
of paradigm also
but it turned out this didn't actually
improve programmer productivity
the thing that improved programmer
productivity was garbage collection
so when you think of a computer first i
mean we kind of have to ask the question
what is a computer
so
you can think about it like you have a
processor that runs a stream of
instructions
and then you have ram um
now you can break ram into two things
there's two things stored in ram there's
instructions
and there's data so most computers
really don't treat these things
very differently when i
make a program like hello world
and i compile this we can take a look
in this program
and that's not even all of it
yeah uh so we have a
this section here this is actually the
ascii for hello world
so it's in the same memory space
um as the instructions itself which does
the
printing of hello world here's the main
function it's called a dialed stub
binder is actually what calls the printf
um so yeah what is a computer uh
processor and ram
um then you can break down
your program so when you have a program
a program has text it's called dot text
which is the instructions
a program has a stack program has a heap
and a program has bss
right so bss are things like um
static data uh there's a stack and then
there's a heap
heaps you get to through malik stacks
you get to through
uh you know anything like
this is a variable on the stack
local vars also control flows on the
stack
right if i have a main function and i
call
a what this does is
pushes the return location
to the stack
so you know when i call b down here
um this at the end here is returned by
popping off
stack okay so this is a basic idea of
what a computer is
now there's a whole other direction you
can go with the idea of what is
programming
right there is a
practical like i want to get a job
right um programming for work
uh maybe we'll make a note too we'll
call programming for
so what does this mean what does a
software engineer do
well they don't really write algorithms
um you will never in any job have to
write
a sort algorithm a binary search
algorithm
anything like that um so they don't
write algorithms
um what else well
very few people actually work on uh
there's some people who work on
infrastructure but that's not a lot of
people
most software engineers are basically
translators
right and they translate a language
uh maybe we'll call the language
business requirements
into code
and there's a whole lot of frameworks
which exist
to make writing things
that meet business requirements easier
if you think of a business requirement
like you know we need a web page that's
going to
allow users to say leave a phone number
where we can call them back right
there's a lot of frameworks that are
designed to do things like that
if you wanted to write something on that
you could use something like ruby on
rails right
and that's why uh i hate when
does that i don't actually know right
for like you know uh web apps
um there's also this paradigm of
crud apps and you get what crud stands
for
uh the four basic types of sql command
create read
update delete all right
uh so let's say we want to build
ruby on rails or similar um
for web apps and you're basically
creating an app that looks like
create read update delete there's some
front end uh the view
there's some database which is the model
and then there is the
uh business logic
which is a controller
so let's say the front end is let's go
back to that um
i want to build a portal
where my customers can uh
add their phone number such that we'll
be able to call them
they have to be able to update their
phone number due to gdpr
they have to be able to delete their
profile you can see how it translates to
this right
um so this isn't this is terrible
you you're not just the same way the
word doctor means so many things a
doctor is someone who diagnoses a doctor
someone who prescribes a doctor or
someone who has bedside manner
um a software engineer
like it's kind of misleading and it's
almost nothing
like what you do in school if you're in
school and you're learning
um how to write binary search algorithms
it's nothing like what you do in
practice what you do in practice is
really you're translating
from a really shitty language um
into these things that are like code and
i meet these people and this is what
you're going to learn
um what you will
learn in boot camps right
um so for example
no one who's ever gone to a boot camp
would ever give get a job at comma ai
because at comma you don't do this um
nothing at comma looks like this
this stupid paradigm and this is the
thing that's going to
be replaced pretty soon by by ai's
i think about writing this
like if you want to write the low brow
version of backspace
backspace is
basically this i mean so here step one
build
a crud app
contracting firm
step two
record all the
inputs of my contract
developers i don't know just say
contract developers will make fun of
someone full-time
uh developers uh train
ai model to translate
business logic into code
right translators
um so yeah if you guys are thinking
uh about a job like this
you know it's it's it's really it's
really trash work
uh you can get paid some amount of money
doing it
but your your your monks used to do this
monks used to like spend time copying
they'd have to before they were
printing presses they'd have to well
someone's got to copy the bible so
that's practically what you're doing
it's not very um
you know it's kind of trash right uh so
notice how none of this
go back to this guy here none of this
has anything to do with this they're
completely separate things
a software engineer a lot of these
people who i meet who are software
engineers
know basically nothing about computers
uh what they know about
is how to translate this shitty language
into code is almost giving it too much
credit
um and then here so let's think of like
like
ruby uh react right
um think of all all the very heavy
frameworks
it almost has nothing to do with
programming and it's like you're
memorizing weird syntax of of
something uh stupid right um
so let's talk about things that are that
are more interesting
all right so uh i come from uh
i learned this stuff from from my kind
of hacking background
um what is happening well so
again programs have input
computation output
so if you want to attack the system
we'll call this a system right
if you want to say get like a uh you
want to get like remote code execution
on the system
right the question you ask is what
input uh
to the system achieves
my uh desired
outcome okay
um so
again a lot of hacking is because like
the the
the system didn't think to check uh for
what it is i'm sending it and you can
get the system to behave in ways
that aren't uh within the normal bounds
of output
so if you think this is actually a
function right um what are the words in
function you have a domain
which is the input to a function
function range
or like you know y equals f of x right
um
so this is a this is a pure model
um but most computation is impure
uh when it's impure the function doesn't
necessarily have to output something in
the range it can do something entirely
different
um
so yeah i mean what is what is hacking
it's figuring
out how uh
the function uh
you know figuring out how to
to make the function uh behave
how uh you want
um now you can use the same
paradigm to analyze almost
anything right input system output
say you want to uh
say you want to change your flight on
united and you don't want to pay change
fees
well you can think of the input is what
can i do well
i have a i can call i can call the
united customer support line
um the system is the customer support
agent and the output
is them clicking a button on their
computer that says wave change fees
probably written in some cred app right
so if you think about it like that you
think okay how do i get the system
what inputs well what do i have control
over i can make multiple calls
i can change the words that i say on
each call
you can do things that are completely
out of bounds of the system entirely you
can
you know get the person's real name you
can dox them uh you can threaten them
you might go to jail for these things
i'm not advising you do it
but it's it's all within this this
paradigm of input
system output and that's what
what is programming input computation
output
thank you for subscribing uh no no there
is uh
it's starting to get big are we getting
people watching the stream
oh yeah okay now let's get viewers let's
get viewers
so when you ask the question
what is programming how do i get good at
programming
i don't understand what it is that you
want
any any website any boot camp
will teach you functioning crud app
programming
um when it comes down to hacking every
system is different if you want to get
good at hacking you just need to
practice
this basic idea uh remember that
one of the reasons i don't play ctfs
anymore is because it
became too um
boxed uh this is i feel similarly about
about competition programming
competition programming is not about who
can cleverly come up with new algorithms
it's just about
you know pattern recognition okay
recognize that
this is actually a a graph isomorphism
problem
uh i can do graphite some isomorphism
that's that's that's np but oh this is
actually
a a binary search over this and i can
sort the list
in n log n instead of n square and i can
solve it in time right
um yeah so cdfs are still fun
and ctf still like i think there's some
that kind of probably break the paradigm
but a lot of it became the same tricks
over and over again and you just drilled
once you can drill it's no longer a test
of intelligence it's a test of like
you know are you willing to practice are
you willing to put
40 hours into a week into learning some
relatively useful skill
i shouldn't hate on ctfs and they're a
great way to get into this stuff it's
just a thing like like
back in the day ctfs didn't feel as much
like this but competition programming
already did
i have nothing but praise for the time
that i spent doing competition
programming
and learning what there is to learn and
then realizing once you're just going to
be grinding it's time to stop
um
yeah uh hacking and coding is all about
learning and applying new skills so
repetition runs counter to what it's all
about okay
um so if you watch my stream two days
ago
where i did the uh adding the for loops
to clang
that's another you can get paid a lot of
money if you can do this right
um this is kind of what my ethereum
contract was uh
understand so so maybe there's a like
like like high brow software engineering
understand a complex system
modify the system to
say add a feature
ship the new system
meaning like test well and stuff
so there's there's a whole lot of
software engineering kind of contracts
or jobs that look like this understand a
complex system
modify the system to add a feature ship
the new system um if you
make yourself challenges like that clang
for loop challenge that i showed you
you'll get good at uh at this
um you want to be a ml engineer
well here's the steps to get good at
that
download paper
implement it
keep doing this
until you have skills
ah
no test today slackmage thank you for
subscribing
um
when you guys say i i saw a comment on
one of the on one of the recent youtube
videos where you say
oh if only george would do would do
lessons what is it you want to learn
what is it that that you want to
you want me to do what what what is it
that you think you can't do
um you want how to get a girlfriend
right
uh all right and again let's use the
same
let's use the same the same uh the same
paradigm right
input uh system
output right um so well what are you
going to need is an input to the system
i mean you want a girlfriend you want
you know women um
a system uh like i don't know what you
mean
first can you come up with a definition
uh you know
let's come up with an exact definition
of uh get a girlfriend
right oh not martin's girl's youtube
finance lessons
um all right so first defined get a
girlfriend
now the system is you know uh the the
female mind and let's say the output is
a
uh let's say let's just say it's an
imessage
uh saying uh so we are
uh official now
uh right
right
so i mean you can think about this right
so i mean we can use the same sort of
tricks we used on
uh on the united uh flight attendant
uh you know i'm trying to get the change
fees right like okay
um one thing i've learned studying
pickup
is you don't get better at seducing
women
you just get better at screening women
it's not about convincing women to sleep
with you or date you it's about finding
the women who are already interested in
sleeping with you
or dating you uh so right uh
same sort of approach and you can treat
this like a funnel right so
let's talk about funnels um
[Music]
so this is a classic uh
sales kind of thing uh let's say you
want to
sell cars right same approach same
approach
uh one uh you have the top of the funnel
which is like getting the word out right
you can do this with like advertising
um too many uh you get some people who
visit the dealership
right and this is a funnel let's say
let's say um
let's say a thousand people see your ad
let's say 10 000 people see your ad
um 100 people visit the dealership
uh and let's say you know uh
five by cars right
so what's your your ratio here you have
one percent here and you have a five
percent conversion ratio here
and you're falling off your funnel uh so
you know we can do the exact same thing
here one um
you know 100 uh message
sent to women uh
we can say maybe um 20 replies
uh let's let's let's let's say 30
replies
uh of every one of those we'll say
we have five dates uh
two lays uh one girlfriend right
same same idea right it's just funnels
um so this here is a
thirty percent ratio this is a
uh one whatever that is in percent like
um this is 40 percent and this is 50
right
funnels
1.2 k viewers let's go
ah
no you don't want a vim lesson right
that's like
oh how do i make a product that make me
a millionaire okay
all right i'm getting money
well so the thing about getting money uh
is there's only one way to get money
um this is capitalism uh
capitalism is based around consent
right and this is kind of the beauty of
capitalism uh in capitalism you have a
buyer
uh and you have a seller um and both
parties
uh must consent
to the transaction right
uh so if
you want to uh make a million dollars
the only way to get money
getting money um in a
capitalist system
system is one way to do it and it's
convince
uh others to give it to you
right you can't make money you can't
produce your own money
uh there is one way to get money and
that's to convince other people
to to give it to you uh yeah welcome to
welcome to nba right
um so if you have you know two people
and one guy selling an apple and it's
ten dollars and the other guy's like
i'll give you five dollars for the apple
the seller can now say okay i consent to
your five dollars i don't consent and
there's no transaction
beauty beautiful right um getting money
in the capital system convince others to
give it to you so
to answer your question how do you
get uh make
1 million dollars
from a product well so
you can kind of um all right ready for
some nba i'll give you some
real mba
so you can think about who you want to
target your product
all right you can either make one dollar
from one million people
uh you can get one million dollars
uh from one person and then there's a
whole spectrum in the middle let's say a
thousand dollars from a thousand people
right
and you can think about basically how
much effort you're willing to spend on
the sale
in each case right so here you know
tons can be spent
uh closing the deal here maybe
uh one phone call
maybe let's say uh you know a couple
phone calls can be spent closing the
deal
and this can be like online only right
uh so how do you make a million dollars
from a product well you can either
convince
a million people to give you one dollar
you can convince thousand people to give
you thousand dollars or you can convince
one person to give you a million dollars
right there's no other way to do it
now make it look fancy put a lambo on
the background and post to instagram is
the new warren buffett yeah
i mean but like like this stuff is so
simple
okay i i don't know how anybody's stupid
enough to pay for mbas that basically
like like like
like here you go there you go there
there there's
basically everything you need to know
right there's so much complexity and
depth i can sit here and type forever
if you wanted to go into like detail of
how computers work
but nobody seems to care about stuff
like that i don't think that's what you
guys care about
um
out of a million subs in his gym right
all right
um
all right so yeah look
do i know how to do like this yeah
sure if i cared right
um
so fundamentally you have to again ah
instagram uh is based around consent
right
uh so you have a uh follower
uh and an influencer right this is the
same it's the same basic
market economics except influencer uh
it's the same basic market economics
uh except
it's not money it's it's it's clout it
doesn't it doesn't really matter
the same basic idea so so how do you how
do you get a million subs an insta well
you know convince
uh one million uh people to subscribe to
you
uh now there's a bunch of ways to do
this right so
uh one way to do it is like with uh
appealing content right uh now there's
lots of different things you can appeal
uh based on you can appeal to
you can appeal to novelty uh you can
appeal to
beauty uh you can appeal to
sexuality um
you can you can appeal to to funny right
uh so i mean that's kind of step one and
if you don't have appealing content
you're not gonna get
uh um step two
is be famous uh so this actually works
if you guys remember my
or this is another way to do it if you
guys remember my thing yesterday
um famous works on on a few different
levels right
so you can say there's there's fomo
famous right like you want you want
people who uh
fear missing out right like oh man i
gotta follow this guy right you can use
so you can use fear basically to get
people to follow you um
there's like the car crash mentality
uh which is similar to fear of missing
out except
you know maybe this is fear of missing
something
uh positive uh fear
of missing something negative right
um all right so you know you can take
like like like uh
maybe kanye west is kind of a mix of
both uh lindsay lohan
is very much in the car crash mentality
um
yeah uh and then there is like um you
know
dark arts all right so you can you can
buy followers
uh these followers come from a few
different places there's cracked
accounts
uh there's big there's big russian uh
people who who crack accounts i think
there's some new accounts
right uh you can do little psychological
tricks like
uh make your insta private
uh if you make your instagram private
you again you're you're appealing to
this uh you know what's behind the
curtain
follow to find out bros
uh
can you explain dynamic programming to
you so go on youtube there's plenty of
people who make great graphics
for for what dynamic programming is um
the basic idea is
say you have some function um
you know you have output uh f of x of y
and you can figure out how to define f
of x of y
in terms of say you know f of x minus
one y minus one right
um dynamic programming is you build up
like a table
uh using the previous outputs uh to to
influence the next outputs
but again you know if you're looking for
an exact
topic like that there's plenty of videos
that'll do a better job explaining it
uh than i can
um i like i don't really know and i'm
going to read some comments now and guys
if you could all i will make it
subscriber only if you guys are writing
stupid crap
is this you guys always say oh i want to
learn i want to learn i want to learn
like what is it that you want to learn
do some garbage collection and explain
what malik is
defcon sold out uh
this is actually a really cool stream
thank you uh here so we have
we have a vip um what not to waste your
time on
okay well let's break that down using
the same sort of
uh uh mentality right
so wasting time
uh so the girl last night on the date
told me a very she has a very
interesting life philosophy
um if you guys know the story about the
fox and sour grapes
the fox is out walking he sees a grape
vine and there's a big
juicy bundle of grapes uh sitting up
there he
puts his paws up on the fence and he
tries to reach it and he can't
um he climbs the fence he starts to
climb the fence
but he cuts his paw and then he's like
you know yeah okay those grapes are
probably sour anyway and he walks away
right um so this is the traditional sour
grape story
and usually people who have this you
know those angry sort of people but
her take on it was when she cut her paw
it must have been a divine sign from god
that the grapes were probably poisonous
it's like a positive spin to the sour
grape story
so i don't know um
you know if you go through life
everything that you don't get you just
realize that you didn't want it anyway
and like you really you
put a positive spin on that this is this
is an impenetrable fortress of
uh psychological i don't know but
um wasting time i don't know
right all right so this gets into like
like uh
existentialism right the basic idea of
existentialism
is uh you make your own
uh meaning all right sorry
now you asked if this is all
existentialism is how did people write
really long books about it
and you'll have to ask those people but
so i don't know
um my personal philosophy
is that there's no such thing as wasting
time
like it's a stupid a time is just
wasting time is great
this is the point of time to waste it um
you know maybe maybe i'll add a caveat
to that
don't fall uh in funnels right
um if you are in other people's funnels
um don't be in
skinner boxes
skinner boxes all right
maybe uh um don't fall in funnels
don't be in skinner boxes and don't uh
be influenced
by advertising
can i explain algorithmic complexity
sure um
again let's let's let's see if there's
good content on this already
before i do it uh what is
algorithmic complexity
algorithmic complexity is a measure of
how long an algorithm would take to
complete given input of size n if an
algorithm has to scale it should compute
the result with a finite and practical
time bound even for large values of n
for this reason complexity is calculated
asymptotically as n approaches infinity
that's what big o notation is
well complexity is usually in terms of
okay
um so this is a way of thinking about it
ah how many
operations does it take for an input of
size n
right so you can take sorting algorithms
sorting is usually a good way
to think about complexity um
so you can take like a bubble sort
algorithm right uh
bubble sort in pseudocode is
uh something along the lines of for i in
uh one to n uh for j
in uh i to n
uh or let's say i plus one to n if j
is less than i swap
ah
all right um so
this algorithm is o of n squared
because you see this loop start from
zero i'm not writing lua or nothing
um so this loop is n this loop you can
be like well no the average is actually
n over two but you know
n times n over two is is is uh you know
it's still o of n squared right so this
is an o of n squared sorting algorithm
so you can take other sorting algorithms
other sorting algorithms basically have
this idea of we're going to build up a
tree
so say i want to sort the list you know
three five
four six right um we take a tree
we put seven on the top branch right and
now we say three is three
uh less than or equal to seven
uh it's less than so we'll put it on
this side of the tree okay
and now we do the same thing with four
so we say well okay let's take four four
less than or equal to seven it's less
than seven less than or equal
to three it's it's greater than three so
it goes here right
um six we have the same kind of well
this turned out to not work too well uh
because the height of this tree is
n but let's say i added something like
10 in you know 10 would go here in the
tree
and make my tree too nice uh let's say i
added a five
in right the five would go here in the
tree and the size of this tree
the height of this tree uh is login
right um so that's all the sort
algorithms that are in n log n time
uh basically have some variant of this
right so it's it's it's n
inserts into
a login sized tree
so there are actually sorting algorithms
that run
in o n
ah so we can think about
let's say the list that i'm sorting is
only
um is guaranteed to only be numbers
between one and one hundred
so i can create a maybe something like
hash sort or something
uh i don't know what the name of it is
but oh then sort
so i can create an array like count
sub 100 for
i and 0 to n count sub arr
sub i
plus equals one
right and then i can loop through count
and then i say uh for
well you know just like print um
you want to print out basically the like
like the number
uh count number of times
right um so you see how this is of m
i have one loop going to n and then i
have one loop going to
to to count which can be viewed as like
uh
as like a k and k is small uh
but this obviously only works if your
your total number here
is small uh because the k
if these biggest element in the array
were to grow um
with the length of the array then the
sort would not be o of n but assuming
that it stays at 100
uh this sword is always of n but usually
the smallest sort is ammon
i think maybe that explains it better
than this
no we're not solving any leap codes
um
i'd like to see you improve and open
source system that you'd like to see
improve and follow along as you help
progressing
issues and features people don't want to
learn they want to have your skills yeah
they can get
can i explain binary search time
complexity sure
so binary search
find an element in
a sorted list
something i say is hacking a lot of
times is uh is just binary search by
hand
right um so let's say
let's say let's say you have an oracle
uh
or or you know we'll just we'll just do
it straight up right uh so here's the
sorted list right
um
let's make
all right let's say i want to find 67
right um
so b search 67.
so you start out with defining a uh
a a a low and a high uh so we'll make
the low
uh the beginning of the array and the
high
the length of the array
so i now take the midpoint
let's say i look at the array array
submit is 22.
now i know that it can't possibly
be any of these right so here's my pivot
i say it can't possibly be any of these
because 67 is greater than 22
so we can now say low equals mid
so now i'm just looking at this array
here
so that's the first run of binary search
right um
so again low zero highest length of
array
mid low plus high equals two let's say
mid is one uh so we get 45
low equals mid all right so now now
we're doing it again
uh for this uh and this time mid
is 67 all right run it through so we can
return that we can
figure out what the index uh in the
original array was right
um so notice that this took three steps
which is significantly less than here n
equals 7 because 7 is the length of the
array so binary search runs an o of log
n time
again you can think about it similar to
the tree where you're only walking down
one path
instead let's say instead of this sorted
list being put contiguously
it's a tree how many jumps you're going
to have to take in the tree it's login
what paper can implement beginner ml
engineer well i mean that's a deep
what paper can implement a beginning ml
engineer
oh i don't know about that uh yeah data
science is largely bs
anyone who's teaching you if you're ever
learning
a
like an object level skill you're
probably not learning the right thing
object level skills will die out when
the tools die out
but if you're learning kind of
meta-level skills
then they're never going to
it's like truth about the world right um
are you learning
something from nature or are you
learning something from people
right
if you're learning something from nature
good uh if you're learning something
from people
bad right um so you can you can you can
break
pretty much everything down into into
this paradigm if you're learning like
physics comes from nature learning
physics is good if you're learning
celebrity gossip this is just
arbitrary about people it's bad
um
so you know one of the one of the
founding themes for the college
uh so we reject
uh power over people
um and this will actually make us
ignored by the system
a system cares
deeply about power
over people
embrace power over nature
so yeah um
and then like like like okay so like
answering a question what is data
science right
um if data science if data science means
like
statistics sure
if data science means like um tooling
used
at company x no
let's define f by
for complex s with a positive real part
how do i find
all zeros of the function
that looks oddly like the riemann
hypothesis
um my
most of my math knowledge is in discrete
math
i don't know that much
[Music]
calculus i didn't really know how to do
that i mean i could write a simulator
for that
uh and then we can binary search for
zeros assuming the function's continuous
we can't exactly binary search
uh well those things are going to get
smaller too
complex s with positive real part oh god
i gotta do complex numbers too i don't
really know
um we want to learn how to learn
efficiently learning
strategies i don't know
helm.ai is four years behind
some of these questions like what books
do you recommend how to stay hungry
um elon talks about this a lot right so
you want to build a uh a knowledge tree
right
i build a knowledge tree and that means
that whenever you learn
new information fits into the trade
people who i've met who know
a lot of things it's
not even always that they know um maybe
uh
interpolation
is possible
even if you don't know exactly what's a
note of a tree if you have some nodes
nearby you can kind of interpolate to it
right
um yeah so
it's kind of a framework for
understanding um
you can you can root this knowledge tree
so elon talks about it elon roots
knowledge tree in physics
i root knowledge tree in information
all right so my whole input computation
output
is this this idea of um
information this is a modernist
perspective post-modernist perspective
all right um but but
both of those things are are very very
good ways of understanding
uh so so i mean how to
explain uh anything
i mean you know i some of these were
like how to get a girlfriend right
input system output this is my core
paradigm for understanding anything
this is what richard hamming was
promoted a lot that's that's like like
like a hamming tree guy
coding theory was one of the classes i
took that i couldn't do
it was too hard for me
um i haven't seen
so bezos um
bezos basically uses this this this one
trick
um bazel's operations mastermind right
[Music]
so for example um amazon ships many
packages
uh when amazon negotiates with ups
uh bezos has his guys draw up
a amazon shipping plan right
the plan is uh let's say sales pitch
uh to ups ups
um you know uh
gives real rate right great
pezos wins
and that's that's that is the amazon
trick over and over and over again
uh oh post-structuralism see i like
weird things like this
i really i really want to meet more i
really want to meet more women and
and go on more dates like women who like
study this stuff
you know like like like i met this i
have this dave this one girl at birthday
and she like knew about all this stuff
man
it's it's a whole world it's a whole
world and i try my best to understand it
i feel like i'll always kind of be a
tourist there
um
structuralism proposes that one may
understand human culture by means of a
structure
modeled on language uh this
understanding differs
from concrete reality and abstraction
ideas instead as a third order that
mediates between the two
yeah and then what's downstream of all
this is the is the
is the modern trash yeah
the postmodernists were trolls man
that's i was i was on the phone with my
friend last night and i was like you
know what
i'm a postmodernist like i really i
embrace these
these i hold these truths to be
self-evident
um
yeah yeah bourgeoisie for cow
and they're trolls but they're trolls
who've shaped the modern world
one thing that i wish i'd done
differently when i was younger was
actually i didn't
i rejected almost outright the
humanities
um as being any
uh oh they were trolls people just took
them seriously
i mean they admitted as such i rejected
the humanities is any sort of
uh any sort of source of relevance in my
life
um when as i've grown up i've come to
realize
that
the college and the singularity
the science doesn't matter i i think one
of the greatest
tragedies in history was that these
incredibly intelligent scientists built
a nuclear bomb
and then handed that bomb off to
politicians like they're subservient to
them
what
why
why why is this
why do politicians or those kind of
people have this
power um
so something that is changing uh
throughout history
is power over people um used to be all
used to be everything
all right um if you if you you didn't if
you lived in a tribe
right if you lived in a like a
hunter-gatherer or tribe
um the only thing what what made you
alpha chimp
what made you alpha chimp was was having
power over the other uh the other chimps
uh not having power over nature you
aren't a 10x better hunter there are
there were no 10x better hunters
um but power over people uh
is waning and power over nature
uh is waxing
is the right word
no i don't want top 10 best waxing
salons
what i got waxing like a moon
yeah having increasing its apparent size
i dropped out of philosophy
undergraduate because i realized how
much you were just learning to tell
logically sound stories
to each other about how the world is
i wish i wish there were a place where i
could go to learn
real humanities
it seems like being self-taught in the
humanities is more difficult
um i found a few
you come upon a few texts in there and
there and they're kind of mind-blowing
um start what is literature
uh
yeah you should read this
ah i'm reading that was
kind of the first
when i started to realize that that
there was a huge
path to uh what is what is what is
running a company what is what is being
uh what is being ceo
it's just telling stories all you're
doing is telling stories and
we compete uh the world is a big
competition of these stories
what is the wickensteiner's tiring
debate
i have so much to read i don't know and
i guess
this is a lot of what i've been doing
off stream especially now is is just
it's just reading and i'm not
there's no there's no future in hacking
um there's practically no future in
programming it's not a question of
if the singularity is going to happen
it's a question of when
and what will it look like and it seems
like what it will look like will be a
lot less
shaped by programmers doing the grunt
work and a lot more shaped by who's
telling the best stories
so you know if you want to save the
world better learn how to tell stories
please teach me on becoming an expert in
programming
so wait
hang on what's the central kind of
thesis of
um by the way everybody should read
uh should read turns paper
ramsay wow it's all the same people man
these people are everywhere so all
biologists want to be chemists all
chemists want to be physicists
while physicists want to be
mathematicians all mathematicians want
to be philosophers and all philosophers
want to be employed
um programmers are
are translators yeah uh
right this is this is what most
software engineers do all day
um go learn your stupid frameworks right
but again that's the my
same thing about about data science
right um
you know tooling that
will go out of vogue
no out of vote maybe that's right maybe
that's wrong
uh yeah i met my medic there uh
these basic ideas peter t i read some
new peter kill thing he really went hard
on that
do i think today we have less
revolutionary innovative minds in
general than before no
how many people can you name from the
20th century
like a hundred wait there's there's
there's definitely revolutionary people
around
today i i think i think that who's the
most revolutionary person i think of the
current millennium satoshi nakamoto
if you really want to do things in some
way you got to do them anonymously
ah i mean that that's just
i don't know maybe that's not true but
yeah i mean look
at look at what elon musk is doing right
there there are definitely people
who are alive today who are going to be
remembered in 100 years
i read the annotated turing book yeah
yeah that's why i read the paper uh
i'll i'll show for the book
yeah i recommend that book
what is a good work ethic to have so one
test that i like to use often to ask a
question if somebody's saying something
say would anybody ever say the opposite
right
so if you have a politician who stands
up on stage and says
the children are our future i care about
the children they're not really saying
anything because nobody would ever say
the opposite
so what is a good work ethic to have
i mean it's a meaningless question
because the
like you should slack off a lot
and you know not really pay attention do
things sloppily
yeah said nobody ever
i'm showing for myself man i'm satoshi
uh what's unless wrong
i'm not saying you should do anything
um it's just a framework it's a
framework for thinking
no i see i'm not i'm not i'm really not
interested in answering questions about
myself
why do you care i'm nobody who are you
you're nobody too
oh they're coming after me man oh no
locker doors man
i don't know like it's again people are
boring nature's interesting
i'm a people too i'm pretty boring
have to think about recursion just as a
stack
all right swat on my house oh no this
guy's going to call a swat in my house
no he's not he's banned
crud development will go away yeah but
it will just become
current development will become the most
lowest common denominator
ai you know
who's that guy in office space he's like
well i take the thing from the engineers
and i give it to the i talk to the
customer and i give it to the engineers
right
that's all it's going to be
um constructivist mathematics uh
i'm i'm yeah of course
uh so my understanding of constructivism
uh says that you can't the law of the
excluded middle doesn't apply
uh so you can't just make an assumption
find a contradiction and say therefore
the assumption is true
uh you wouldn't this is why i really
like things like which
like so they have a constructivist
which um
it says if you want to say something's
true you can't just say you can't just
like yeah find a contradiction
uh so i think that
like finitism i believe is true in a
deep philosophical sense um whereas
constructivism
is just another lens uh
where are the differences what can you
not
what can you say in non-constructivist
mathematics
uh that you can't say in constructivist
or just proofs harder
taking the principle of the excluded
middle from the mathematician would be
the same
say as prescribing the telescope to an
astronomer or the box of the use of his
fists
um
yeah so so yeah
ah construct
is google gonna actually give me
anything for this i want
non-constructivist truths
you can't derive in constructivism
oh i'll say
oh god yeah aaron schwartz take down j
store j store
some like learning theory i don't know
about that yeah
what i want to know is like like yeah
what are the truths right and then do
they feel
i don't know i mean i like like
intuitionism as well
um
it's one thing to innovate in the
computer science world but it's another
thing to utilize it to make money which
is where you need translators to deliver
uh so uh what is money
right all
uh i mean okay uh
[Music]
it gets i'm not gonna go into this but
if your goal in life is to make money
all i will say is that is never for
anybody a terminal goal
making money cannot be a terminal goal
right
money money itself does not have any
intrinsic value money only has
always think about what your terminal
values are right
um
this is uh let's find the
slate star codex society
shocks
uh yes
bostrom makes an offhanded reference of
the possibility of a dictatorless
dystopia one that every single citizen
including the leadership
hates but which nevertheless endures
unconquered it's easy enough to imagine
such a state imagine a country with two
rules
first every person must spend eight
hours a day giving themselves strong
electric shocks
second if anyone fails to follow a rule
including this one or speaks out against
there fails to enforce it
all citizens must unite to kill that
person suppose these rules were well
enough established by tradition that
everyone expected them to be enforced
so you shock yourself for eight hours a
day because you know if you don't
everyone else will kill you because if
they don't everyone else will kill them
and so on
i heard the russians used a similar
tactic in order to prevent defection in
world war
ii uh you know a soldier on the front
line who's being told to charge a
machine gun turret might want to run the
other way
but you know it is the job of everybody
behind them to shoot all the cowards
and if you do not shoot a coward you're
a coward yourself and you'll be shot by
somebody else
dictatorless dystopia so
think about what you really want money
for and are we really just in one of
these dictators dystopias
there's my viewer count he's gone
and coward is whatever is defined by the
russian system right
are we running out of innovative ideas
no
oh here we go easy example of a
non-constructivist proof without an
obvious fix
some digit occurs infinitely often in
the decimal expansion of pi
have we proven that
oh some digit occurs okay
perhaps you think of the statement that
every digit occurs infinitely often
which is probably open
yeah um but some digit occurs infinitely
often
uh i mean yeah okay you're right so the
obvious proof there is
assume for the sake of contradiction
that no digits occur
infinitely often then given that there's
a finite number of digits
uh by the pigeonhole principle
pi is not a transcendent number but we
know pi is a transcendent number
uh therefore contradiction
uh qed um
this is another classic one yeah
i mean but i'm sure you can prove that
uh the square root of two's irrational
uh i'm sure you can prove that in a
constraint
constructivist proof
square root to uh irrational
direct proof of irrationality
a simple direct proof that i found as a
teenager
theorem
it can conduct our ideal
what that's confusing
okay theorem is that it's integral
if rational so meaning it's an integer
if it's if it's rational
uh the proof
okay so it's a reduced fraction so the
greatest common divisor is one
uh that's using like the extended
euclidean algorithm
yeah that works sure
yeah there you go it's so much better
it's so much better than the other proof
oh browering can are examples let's say
i think that all of higher education
today is whatever the opposite of based
is you know maybe cupped
uh that's kind of a problem
like there's probably small numbers of
holdouts
in these
tentacles institutions
uh rise of
administration
costs in colleges
uh yeah all right there we go it's it's
there uh put it this way administrative
spending comprised just 26 percent of
total educational spending by american
colleges
uh three decades later admitted no it's
not
wait huh where'd the other spending go
i don't know ah
maybe this isn't true i'm not i'm not
that interested in looking into the case
uh i mean i witnessed this firsthand
i've heard
from speaking with a lot of people uh
just how
this is what i mean
uh that's that's not what i was thinking
of
but
yeah i'm not i'm not i'm not hopeful for
the future of the the higher education
system
uh curtis describes it as a state church
where do i expect newer generations to
learn things like lower level
programming or theory the same place
everyone else did what do you mean
people always say this people say this
about computer science man the kids
aren't really going to learn how
computers work
why because our math majors don't know
how arithmetic works
like that's just a sign that someone was
poorly educated
not it's not going to like fade from the
world people say this but
you know there's been so many other
disciplines and i have no idea why they
think
computer science is going to be
different
look up the journal constructive
approximation
there's so much to learn guys
i don't really know what approximations
and expansions
are
by the way oh i mean unfortunately it's
a web archive but can we look at how
nice this web page is
someone criticized my uh
use of like looking at the
sh the form and not the content but the
form is an
incredibly good predictor of content a
website like this
contains truths because there's no other
reason for someone to build it
unfortunately it's been taken offline
let's see
a website like this probably contains
way less truths
right compare the websites
so now we see what's wrong with uh
colleges
i promise our university
will have a website that looks much more
like this and much less like this
computer architecture or quantitative
approach let's see what we got
college is a funnel society's a funnel
man
what i want to show me the uh
don't show me the table of contents
he's the president of stanford
i tried yeah i click off the kindle
version i i think
i don't think anywhere ah take a look
inside oh cool
see what we got
i mean this is yeah if you want to study
computer architecture that's like a
decent
oh now this is i mean this is from
google what
takes like uh 10 nanoseconds
to get to uh l1 cache
100 nanoseconds to get to l2 takes like
a microsecond to get to memory and it
takes like a millisecond to get to disk
or whatever those numbers are you should
know that understand all of that
memory hierarchy there's an old saying
like there's two hard problems in
computer science
it's like search and caching or
something
um that's the quote
cash and validation and naming things
know that you are problems in computer
science cash and validation naming
things and off by one errors
let's see
cool
how do you get over a thousand people to
watch you rant about how
you they shouldn't need to watch people
like you rant
i don't know we're just hanging out and
like thinking i'm gonna go back to
reading in a bit
i try my ideas out on twitch right i
tried hammer out and decided there's
never gonna be a hammer
hammer um i tried backspace out
and it got a pretty good response on
twitch um
the problems with backspace are more
technical and actually comes down to
more the question of what is programming
right i don't want to make if you want
to do programming for work if you want
to make crud apps like
that's not really what i want to do in
backspace
um i mean the
the problem i ran into with backspace
is like um is
our modern programming languages
already the best way
to describe what you want
how yeah
like yeah what is it is programming
really just describing
is is there a more concise language
that's probably a better way
to is does there
exist a more concise
programming language
um aka
uh what is the next
gc right
object-oriented programming didn't
deliver the improvements garbage
collection did
uh not having to deal with freeing your
memory
um i mean so so
my basic thesis is like uh compilers
should do more search
gc is garbage collection uh so if i
write some
if i write some c code
let's make a function
all right so that's all well and good
except for this fact
see look at a dot out's memory usage
right
it's memory usage is growing and we're
going to have to kill it before it keeps
using more because there's a memory leak
because what happens in this program is
every time a is called
i'm malicking six bytes of memory i'm
taking six bytes
off the heap and even though once this
while loop comes around again those
bytes are never accessible
um it doesn't matter
the compiler the program's already
allocated them so you know to fix this
bug
i can do that
and now we'll see that a dot out does
not increase in memory usage
right so a gc would automatically find
unreachable pointers and free them
yeah so rust has a separate idea russ
has this idea of of uh of ownership
um but it makes rust very very hard to
code
the the beauty of gcs is that they
operate completely in the background and
it would make this a valid program to
run
i could write this in go and go as a gc
and it's fine
if you can find the shortest program
that outputs the data yeah sure um i
shall for the hudder prize a lot
make it subscribers only you never see
my chat i see your chat and you're a
subscriber
um all right
we'll be right back and then we'll do
we'll do subscriber only q a and then go
back to reading
what problems are we solving today no
real problems
shining like a diamond what are you
reading from
i'm almost done with my uh my book from
yesterday white noise
what is this dud baiting twitch prime
dot can we do a meet up before the
singularity
what happens if you pass string copy a
character array without a null
terminator
um i mean it'll just keep copying to
whatever on the stack till it finds it
i'll terminator
is it any indication that we're not
close to an efficient to write language
when we have functional programming
that's so fundamentally different
i mean um are getting better i i'm very
oh man you know what i'd give to code in
the language 20 years from now
oh i'd be so happy
cameo.com what was that
i was just like i can book like famous
people to come to my party
look at personalized messages wow
oh i got to think about my brand you
know
and how to solve constant growth of
misinformation
i mean has that ratio actually gotten
worse
has the ratio of information to
misinformation changed
i'm not sure it has
how does one be motivated oh
this is dumb questions like think of why
that's a dumb question
what are you one one way to ask
if if something's a dumb question or not
is like think about what the structure
of the answer you want is
what kind of structure like like like
what is the space what does the range
look like of the
what does the output space look like
like
you are the kind of person who deserves
google
right because this one weird trick to
stay motivated
is is what you're looking for there and
that's the only answer you're going to
get and it's not a real answer so
your curiosity is never going to be
satiated and you're going to keep
googling that same crap
over and over and over again there's not
an answer
there's less hierarchy and information
distribution
i'm not even sure about that
so think about in some ways there's more
hierarchy right um
oh that's all right let me see if i can
find i wish i had a nice way to index
this book better
um
about families
let's find the exact quote they put in
the book a lot better i'm gonna say it
but
families are held together based on in
um
on untruths and and commonly shared lies
i think that despite
people talking a lot about
misinformation
in in some ways from my perspective when
people are screaming about fake news
what they're actually mad about when
they keep talking about misinformation
is actually that they don't control the
narrative anymore
it's not that the new narratives are any
less true than the old narratives the
old narratives are all lies as well
it's just there's a different kind of
group providing the new narratives the
new narratives are coming from a
different place
and i think there is slightly more true
than the old narratives but only
slightly
any advice to crack fang interviews
all right honestly
if they sit you down and they're like do
two lead code hard problems
this is why i'm not doing lead code on
stream for you guys it's like
why waste your time memorizing that
they're no it's
just insulting i mean i think it's
insulting to to everybody
uh who's being interviewed like
they're not checking to see whether
you're a good programmer or not they're
checking to see whether you're willing
to grind for hours and hours and hours
right delete code grind is real like is
that is that the kind of organization
you want to go work at
an organization that values you just
grinding on something stupid and
irrelevant for hours
um that said i think that uh programming
challenges are an incredible way to
judge
um candidates but
not timed ones right
we have a like
or at least not time crunch in front of
a person
uh we we have a we have a hackering
challenge for for comma
um but we give you four hours and if
you're good you can do it in under an
hour
it's it's not designed to be
it's designed to be a freshman weeder
test not some insane
this is how we're truly going to judge
you
the speed challenge yeah i like the
speed challenge it's kind of
it's more open-ended but it has it's
it's more open-ended but it has a clear
rigid evaluation criteria uh it's an
import it's important to have
interviews that are have clear
evaluation criteria to avoid bias
don't take amphetamines um so
my experience with uh amphetamines
adderall stimulants
is they do not make you better at things
they make you think you're better at
things
they they trigger
this delusion uh
if i am good at something i want to
believe i am good at something if i am
bad at something i want to believe i am
bad at something
nootropics are mostly a scam
i think humanities will ever be able to
escape structures and hierarchies within
nature that
combat transhumanism i'm not sure
exactly what that means
honesty doesn't give deep thoughts it
makes you think all your thoughts are
deep
i have more positive things to say about
lsd than i do about
uh amphetamines
i think lsd shows you something
and uh
i mean like with all drugs you know
understand what it has to teach you and
then stop
i think i want to go to one of those
10-day meditation retreats
uh but i don't know i don't want to talk
about drugs they're not drugs aren't
that interesting
joshua new god of transhumanism
uh what's the happiest memory i don't
really like talking about myself either
most of these things here i don't really
talk about myself i do give anecdotes
for my wife they're
they're more to illustrate a point uh
because anything that i say about myself
is personal and useless to you
don't be like me it's dumb
you know i'm trying to give you
information so you can think
don dele white noise
some of the stories are made up yeah
doesn't matter
uh i've been drinking recess yeah it's
kind of nice
i've never read your class elements all
right cool
um
it's about pascal's wager
pascal's mugging yeah
heh
it's a funny idea
and this is why i'm not a
consequentialist
many mangoes that is kind of funny
things
by oh oh you mean just things in general
oh i felt like things was like uh yeah
of course
web app frameworks like electron why
don't we ship the operating system in
every uh
electron is just docker man it's the
same idea no
i don't want i don't know anything that
makes deployment development easier is
probably good
stanislaw lim
can you think of any fun problems to
tackle in your retails
if you come up with one
hmm no
it is it's in local folder i'm probably
much more likely to lose it than the
cloud
the is a tc if you want a high
tc you gotta play the game
you know what there is a star trek
voyager episode
tc yes treatment coefficient yes
yes critical care yes
just as the doctor asks what tc stands
for
oh total compensation oh you mean the
team blinds
oh my god oh my god
it's pascal's mugging man
yeah i'd like to go to today
the problem is i have to like schedule
it months in advance
worldsignia yt thank you for subscribing
turning into a lizard man i love voyager
growing up you know
i just want to know where i learned
morality from star trek voyager
so whatever janeway believed that i
believe
alright guys thank you for watching the
stream um if you enjoyed today's stream
i'm gonna look at my revenues and if i
got a lot of revenue for this stream
we're gonna do more streams like this
one
but i don't know i'm probably not gonna
stream for a bit
it's the weekend i got things to do that
aren't streaming
uh please subscribe if you haven't
subscribed it
we like subscribers somebody asked me
earlier do i believe that there are
some people are better than others yes i
believe that subscribers are better than
non-subscribers
rex doors thank you for subscribing
can you do an irl stream
should i like rent out a you know you
know like they're hyped on the covet
um
feels good man subs rise up yeah there's
a class system
all twitches aren't equal they're
subscribers and non-subscribers i don't
i don't tell lies you know i'm a flex
thank you for gifting subs um
today's dream is top tier i'm glad you
liked it yeah just get a mask or
something with my mask
that's right let's show it boys
today's flow is better thank you
what's ocsp
oh just some like certification thing
vic jack thank you for subscribing
uh
facetime is still funny um
subscriber power full lidar
you take care too real port your
subscriber your good person
um yeah not have any certifications
don't don't take me over security itself
is all it's all
racket first we got to scare them about
hackers then we got to sell them the
anecdote to hackers antidote yeah
thank you uh ranch leo thank you for
subscribing there's a take on
morality of piracy i don't believe in
universal morality or ethics
make up your own mind man
um anybody who's trying to but i do
dislike anybody who tries to preach to
you morality or ethics
tries to tell you how you should act man
because that's just powerful people
moral relativist i have personal borrows
i talk about yeah like i said i don't
really like talking about my
only streams i don't really think i talk
about like myself
right like even this this is not really
a comment about myself this is a comment
about the content
of the streams
i post more instagram pics
all right well you know what if i find
out about this
we're never streaming again you're
banned and you know what people
dm me all the time my dms are full of
can you please unban me yo dude can you
unban me sir yo can you unban me
bro you're banned for life
i don't think jaime was a more relative
of a style that's true
can i ban you i'm not gonna ban you
you're a subscriber
you're a good person
uh good i'm glad
if ro jogen was like a mockery of the
podcast
i would totally go on road joking like a
mockery of that whole format
rojo again yo is there really a road
joking let's check it out
ro jogen
um
laser cap boss you're close to getting
banned
you don't care if you're a subscriber
bro jogin
there's nothing wrong with the format it
has more to do with the reach
this is why i wouldn't go on joe rogan
i just imagined saris wasn't that the
bad guy in galaxy quest
alright guys thank you all for watching
good afternoon learn real things